ANUPAMA M A

Software Engineer (ML/DL)

Location : Chennai, Tamil Nadu E-mail ID : anupamamanikandan94@gmail.com

Phone Number: +91 91883 05357, +91 62824 45230 **Date of Birth**: 25th February 1994

PROFILE SUMMERY

Software Engineer (ML/DL) with 2+ years of experience in building algorithms and predictive models. Worked on clustering & classification, data analysis & visualization as well as hands-on experience in image processing and natural language processing methods. Passionate, quick learner with good communication skills.

SKILLS

Technical Skills

- Deep Learning Architectures, Neural Networks, SVM, Image Processing, NLP
- Linear/Logistic Regression, Clustering, Graph Theory, Regularization, Optimization

Tools

• Anaconda, Jupyter, Visual Studio, Matlab

Soft Skills

- Written and Verbal Communication
- Analytical Thinking

- TensorFlow, Keras, OpenCV, NLTK, SciKit Learn, Pandas, NumPy, MatplotLib
- Python, C++
- Requirements Engineering
- MS Office, Google Workspace
- Adaptability & Flexibility
- Collaboration

EXPERIENCE

ZF-Wabco India Limited Software Engineer (ML/DL)

Chennai, India (07/2019-Present)

- Worked on Vehicle Telematics for collecting valuable information from vehicle via CAN, processing them and transmitting them to cloud also for specifying system level requirements as well as system architecture.
- Worked on Terrain Classification for classifying the road surface using multiple deep learning models.
- Worked on Driver Monitoring System designing the cloud computing architecture as well as specifying feature level requirements and integrating the 3rd party SDKs into an embedded device by writing a wrapper function.
- Worked on Traffic Sign Recognition for classifying various traffic signs using multiple deep learning algorithms and integrating the models in Android app.
- Worked on developing the concept of Prognostic Diagnostics for using past and present vehicle data for validating the feasibility of data, predicting vehicle's condition and future maintenance requirements.

ZF-Wabco India Limited Student Trainee/Intern

Chennai, India (08/2018-07/2019)

• Worked on Requirements Robot project to help user overcome various requirements writing challenges such as duplicate requirements and requirements not written according to guidelines using Natural Language Processing.

EDUCATION

Amrita Vishwa VidyapeethamCoimbatore, IndiaM-Tech Computational Engineering and Networking(03/2017-04/2019)Heera College of Engineering and TechnologyTrivandrum, IndiaB-Tech Electronics and Communication Engineering(03/2012-03/2016)

PUBLICATIONS

Breast Cancer Classification using Capsule Network with Preprocessed Histology Images IEEE, ICCSP, Chennai

Anupama M A, Sowmya V, Soman K P. 2019

Springer, ISMAC-CVB, Namakkal

Vimal Kurup R, Anupama M A, Vinayakumar R, Sowmya V, Soman K P.

Capsule Network for Plant Disease and Plant Species Classification

2019

CERTIFICATIONS

QR6S Yellow Belt Certification – Unexpected delay during FOTA POC testing

Machine Learning by Andrew Ng

Deep Learning prerequisites: The Numpy Stack in Python

Wabco, 2021

Coursera, 2018

Udemy, 2017

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Languages: English, Malayalam

Place: Chennai Anupama M A